<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>L09 SUMO EXTRAVAGANZA</title>
 <link href="http://l09-sumo.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://l09-sumo.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2016-10-27T23:59:20+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://l09-sumo.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Joakim Wimmerstedt</name>
   <email>joakim.wimmerstedt@hyperisland.se</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Results and code</title>
   <link href="http://l09-sumo.github.io/2016/10/27/last-post/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://l09-sumo.github.io/2016/10/27/last-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Second place!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compadres, it&amp;rsquo;s with honor and a tear slowly rolling down my cheek that I get to say these final words to you. Pentabot was amazing in the tournament and actually placed second. That&amp;rsquo;s not bad considering we were 16 teams competing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Pre-tournament alterations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of days before the tournament we decided to change the construction of Pentabot. We needed a lower front that actually covered the wheels. I think this is what actually helped us get a high placement. Most robots we met tried to get under our front but failed to do so. We also had an advantage in that we seemed to have quicker turning speed than the others, and that&amp;rsquo;s mostly because we actually tried out different turning speeds and found that too much and we&amp;rsquo;d overshoot the target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t have any pictures to share, I can share the actual code we used. It&amp;rsquo;s commented in swedish for learning purposes. You can find it over at our github page: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/l09-sumo/sumo&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing Pentabot</title>
   <link href="http://l09-sumo.github.io/2016/10/06/pentabot/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://l09-sumo.github.io/2016/10/06/pentabot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well boys, we did it. We finished our lego bot. Pentabot (named after the five wheels he&amp;rsquo;s resting on) will be going ham on the competition in the final sumo tournament next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s looking forward to taking home his first title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://l09-sumo.github.io/assets/images/pentabot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pentabot looking smashing&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to program your Lego Bot with NXC (on a Mac)</title>
   <link href="http://l09-sumo.github.io/2016/09/19/NXC-on-mac/"/>
   <updated>2016-09-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://l09-sumo.github.io/2016/09/19/NXC-on-mac</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When starting with Lego programing, Mac users are often met with difficulties when it comes to language selection. Whilst many languages exist that one could write mindstorm-programs with, not many are OSX compatible. In reality - the only viable option apart from the visual lego language is NXC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with NXC is however also a big hurdle if you&amp;rsquo;re not used to working with the terminal. Here&amp;rsquo;s where this short guide comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;ll need&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started with developing there&amp;rsquo;s a few things you&amp;rsquo;ll need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your charged lego robot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A text editor (I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; from Github!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A USB-cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets start off by downloading the files we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lego.com/sv-se/mindstorms/downloads&quot;&gt;mindstorms downloads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll down to &amp;ldquo;NEDLADDNING AV NXT-PROGRAMVARA (PC/MAC)&amp;rdquo; and select the NXT Fantom driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the NXT Fantom Driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bricxcc.sourceforge.net/nbc/release/index.html&quot;&gt;bricxcc sourceforge page for NBC&lt;/a&gt; and download the latest executable for Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extract the contents for the .tgz-file you just downloaded in a location of your choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Using NXC and running the code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While developing, you write your code in a text editor as per the NXC documentation. When you want to try out the code on the robot, you do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open up a terminal and navigate to the folder. If you placed the contents on your desktop, the command you need to run will be &lt;code&gt;cd ~/Desktop/&amp;lt;name of the folder&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plug in your lego robot to your mac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the following command and replace &amp;ldquo;file-path&amp;rdquo; with the path to your .nxc file. If you&amp;rsquo;re having trouble finding the path, simply drag the .nxc file into the terminal window.
&lt;code&gt;./nbc -d file-path&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to, you can replace the &amp;ldquo;-d&amp;rdquo; with a &amp;ldquo;-r&amp;rdquo; to execute the code automatically when it&amp;rsquo;s downloaded to the robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all there is to it! Happy Hacking! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/DBfYJqH5AokgM/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;hacking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The beginning</title>
   <link href="http://l09-sumo.github.io/2016/09/08/First_post/"/>
   <updated>2016-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://l09-sumo.github.io/2016/09/08/First_post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a part in the course Engineering Methods (II3000 @ KTH) all students are expected to form groups and design, construct and program a Lego Robot using a Lego Mindstorm/NXT kit provided by the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The robots are then set to compete against eachother in a tournament where the goal is to push the opponent outside of a ring. It&amp;rsquo;s called The Sumo Challenge, and is a concept that has been used at numerous institutions all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re a group of four students working together to try and find the best possible designs for how to deal with this challenge. This is the first entry in many documenting our process throughout the project. We are excited to make our mark in the Lego Sumo community and we look forward to winning the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example on what we &lt;strong&gt;won&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; create, here&amp;rsquo;s a video:
&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    &amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; Copy &amp;amp; Pasted from YouTube &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UIWWLg4wLEY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
